<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
        <string name="feverDES"><li> Examine your symptoms and take your temperature. A fever is defined as a temperature of 100.4°F (38°C) or above.
            Rest and stay in bed.</li><br/>
            <li>
Keep yourself hydrated. To replace fluids lost via sweating, drink water, iced tea, or very diluted juice. If keeping liquids down is tough, eat ice chips instead.
</li><br/>
<li>
Fever can be treated with over-the-counter drugs such as acetaminophen and ibuprofen. Take note of the correct amount and avoid taking them with other fever-relieving drugs. You should see your doctor before giving aspirin to your newborn or toddler. Ibuprofen should not be administered to infants under the age of six months.
</li><br/>
<li>
Keep your cool. Unless you have the chills, remove extra layers of clothing and blankets.
</li><br/>
            <li>
Make yourself more comfortable by taking mild baths or applying cold compresses. Alcohol baths or rubs, as well as cold baths, ice cube baths, and ice cube baths, should all be avoided.
</li><br/>
            <li>
However, regardless of the temperature reading on the thermometer, if you have any concerns, visit your doctor
        </li>
        </string>

    <string name="stomachDES">1: Drinking water
It is said that water is the ultimate solution for every problem so for an upset stomach. The body needs water to absorb essential nutrients and helps to eliminate the toxic substance from your body. Being dehydrated may lead to stomach upset due to vomiting and diarrhea.

2: Lemon water
Lemon water is an excellent option in indigestion. We always opt for lemon water whenever we feel abdominal discomfort. The alkaline effect of lemon helps in soothing the excess acidity in the stomach.

3: Baking soda and lemon drink
It is an easy and the best option for indigestion. You can mix lemon juice in water with a pinch of baking soda that may help to relieve digestive complaints. The drink produces carbonic acid in the stomach, causing the reduction of indigestion and gas. The acid in lemon also reduces the acid secretion in your stomach.

4: Mint
Mint leaves contain menthol that helps to make your stomach calm and reduce indigestion problems. It also helps in reducing muscle spasms in the intestines and relieve pain. Mint is a traditional treatment for indigestion in Asian countries.

5: Ginger
Ginger used since ancient times for cold, cough, nausea, vomiting, and pain. It contains chemicals called-gingerols and shogaols. These chemicals can help speed up stomach contractions leads to reduce abdominal pain.

6: Cinnamon
Cinnamon sticks are rich in various antioxidants such as camphor, cinnamaldehyde, linalool, and eugenol. It helps your stomach to digest the food easily. It helps to treat symptoms like bloating, nausea, and fullness of the abdomen.

7: Cumin
Cumin seeds are one of the best solutions for an upset stomach when you want instant results. It helps in reducing hyperacidity, gaseous distention of the abdomen, and pain.</string>

    <string name="wristPainDES">
Most cases of hand and wrist pain will not be a sign of a serious or long-term problem and will settle in a few days or weeks with some simple self-care you can do at home.
Putting an ice pack on your hands and wrists can reduce swelling and ease pain. You could use a packet of frozen peas wrapped in a damp towel. Never put ice directly on your skin, as this can burn or irritate it. You can apply ice for up to 20 minutes several times a day.

If your hands are painful and stiff, applying heat could help. There are products such as wheat bags you can buy from chemists that you heat in a microwave. You might need to place a cloth or tea towel on your skin to avoid burning it. Putting your hand and wrist on a hot water bottle with the cover on, or having a warm bath or shower may also provide some relief. Moving your hand around in a bowl of warm water can be helpful and soothing. Don’t apply heat to your hand or wrist if it’s swollen or if you’ve just injured it, as this can make it worse.

Wax baths are another form of heat therapy that can relieve pain and stiffness. To get the most benefit it’s a good idea to use one before you exercise your hands. Ask your GP, a pharmacist or a hand therapist where you can buy one, and for advice on how to use them. Follow the instructions carefully, and make sure you don’t overheat the wax. You shouldn’t use these if you have cuts or open sores.

Switching between heat and ice therapy throughout the day may help. Ice reduces blood flow, which can help with pain and swelling. Heat increases blood flow, which can help if your hands are stiff and the muscles are tired. Heat can also help damaged soft tissue to heal.

Wearing splints
Wearing splints can provide support to the hand and wrist. Some can be used when you’re carrying out everyday activities and some are for when you’re sleeping and resting. A hand therapist, physiotherapist or occupational therapist can give you advice on whether a splint could help, which type would be good for you and how to use it properly.

Keeping your hands and wrists moving
Moving your hands, wrists and fingers as much as possible can help ease pain and stiffness. This will also maintain range of movement, function and strength.
    </string>
    <string name="legPainDES">
        You can usually treat leg pain at home if it’s due to cramps or a minor injury. Try the following home treatments when your leg pain is from muscle cramps, fatigue, or overuse:

Rest your leg as much as possible, and elevate your leg with pillows.
Take an over-the-counter pain reliever, such as aspirin or ibuprofen, to help ease discomfort as your leg heals.
Wear compression socks or stockings with support.
Apply ice
Apply ice to the affected area of your leg at least four times per day. You can do this even more frequently in the first few days after the pain appears. You can leave the ice on for as long as 15 minutes at a time.

Take a warm bath and stretch
Take a warm bath, and then gently stretch your muscles. If you have pain in the lower part of your leg, try pointing and straightening your toes when sitting or standing. If you have pain in the upper part of your leg, try to bend over and touch your toes.

You can do this while sitting on the ground or standing up. Ease into each stretch, holding each position for five to 10 seconds. Stop stretching if your pain gets worse.You can help prevent medical conditions that may cause nerve damage in the legs by doing the following:

Exercise for 30 minutes per day, five days per week.
Maintain a healthy weight.
Avoid smoking.
Monitor your cholesterol and blood pressure, and take steps to keep them under control.
Limit your alcohol consumption to one drink per day if you’re a woman or two drinks per day if you’re a man.
    </string>
    <string name="ThroatPainDES">
        You can treat most sore throats at home. Get plenty of rest to give your immune system a chance to fight the infection.

To relieve the pain of a sore throat:

Gargle with a mixture of warm water and 1/2 to 1 teaspoon of salt.
Drink warm liquids that feel soothing to the throat, such as hot tea with honey, soup broth, or warm water with lemon. Herbal teas are especially soothing to a sore throat (5Trusted Source).
Cool your throat by eating a cold treat like a popsicle or ice cream.
Suck on a piece of hard candy or a lozenge.
Turn on a cool mist humidifier to add moisture to the air.
Rest your voice until your throat feels better.    </string>
    <string name="EyePainDES">
The treatment for eye pain depends on the cause of the pain. The most common treatments include:

Home care
The best way to treat many of the conditions that cause eye pain is to allow your eyes to rest. Staring at a computer screen or television can cause eyestrain, so your doctor may require you to rest with your eyes covered for a day or more.

Glasses
If you frequently wear contact lenses, give your corneas time to heal by wearing your glasses.

Warm compress
Doctors may instruct people with blepharitis or a sty to apply warm, moist towels to their eyes. This will help to clear the clogged oil gland or hair follicle.

Flushing
If a foreign body or chemical gets into your eye, flush your eye with water or a saline solution to wash the irritant out.

Antibiotics
Antibacterial drops and oral antibiotics may be used to treat infections of the eye that are causing pain, including conjunctivitis and corneal abrasions.

Antihistamines
Eye drops and oral medicines can help ease the pain associated with allergies in the eyes.

Eye drops
People with glaucoma may use medicated eye drops to reduce the pressure building in their eyes.

Corticosteroids
For more serious infections, such as optic neuritis and anterior uveitis (iritis), your doctor may give you corticosteroids.

Pain medications
If the pain is severe and causes an interruption to your day-to-day life, your doctor may prescribe a pain medicine to help ease the pain until the underlying condition is treated.

Surgery
Surgery is sometimes needed to repair damage done by a foreign body or burn. However, this is rare. Individuals with glaucoma may need to have a laser treatment to improve drainage in the eye.
    </string>

    <string name="HeadachesDES">
        Headaches are a very common condition that most people will experience many times during their lives. The main symptom of a headache is a pain in your head or face. This can be throbbing, constant, sharp or dull. Headaches can be treated with medication, stress management and biofeedback.1. Drink Water
Inadequate hydration may lead you to develop a headache.

In fact, studies have demonstrated that chronic dehydration is a common cause of tension headaches and migraines (1).

Thankfully, drinking water has been shown to relieve headache symptoms in most dehydrated individuals within 30 minutes to three hours (2Trusted Source).

What’s more, being dehydrated can impair concentration and cause irritability, making your symptoms seem even worse.
To help avoid dehydration headaches, focus on drinking enough water throughout the day and eating water-rich foods.


2. Take Some Magnesium
Magnesium is an important mineral necessary for countless functions in the body, including blood sugar control and nerve transmission (3Trusted Source).

Interestingly, magnesium has also been shown to be a safe, effective remedy for headaches.

Evidence suggests that magnesium deficiency is more common in people who get frequent migraine headaches, compared to those who don’t (4).

Studies have shown that treatment with 600 mg of oral magnesium citrate per day helped reduce both the frequency and severity of migraine headaches (3Trusted Source, 5).

However, taking magnesium supplements can cause digestive side effects like diarrhea in some people, so it’s best to start with a smaller dose when treating headache symptoms.

You can find magnesium supplements online.

3. Limit Alcohol
While having an alcoholic drink may not cause a headache in most people, studies have shown that alcohol can trigger migraines in about one-third of those who experience frequent headaches (6Trusted Source).

Alcohol has also been shown to cause tension and cluster headaches in many people (7Trusted Source, 8Trusted Source).

It’s a vasodilator, meaning it widens blood vessels and allows blood to flow more freely.

Vasodilation may cause headaches in some people. In fact, headaches are a common side effect of vasodilators like blood pressure medications (9Trusted Source).

Additionally, alcohol acts as a diuretic, causing the body to lose fluid and electrolytes through frequent urination. This fluid loss can lead to dehydration, which can cause or worsen headaches (10Trusted Source).

4. Get Adequate Sleep
Sleep deprivation can be detrimental to your health in many ways, and may even cause headaches in some people.

For example, one study compared headache frequency and severity in those who got less than six hours of sleep per night and those who slept longer. It found that those who got less sleep had more frequent and severe headaches (11Trusted Source).

However, getting too much sleep has also been shown to trigger headaches, making getting the right amount of rest important for those looking for natural headache prevention (12).

For maximum benefits, aim for the “sweet spot” of seven to nine hours of sleep per night (13Trusted Source).

5. Avoid Foods High in Histamine
Histamine is a chemical found naturally in the body that plays a role in the immune, digestive and nervous systems (14Trusted Source).

It’s also found in certain foods like aged cheeses, fermented food, beer, wine, smoked fish and cured meats.

Studies suggest consuming histamine may cause migraines in those who are sensitive to it.

Some people are not able to excrete histamine properly because they have impaired function of the enzymes responsible for breaking it down (15Trusted Source).

Cutting histamine-rich foods from the diet may be a useful strategy for people who get frequent headaches (16Trusted Source).
    </string>

    <string name="footPainDES">
        If you have a toothache, it’s important to figure out what’s at the root of your discomfort. From there, you can determine how to best relieve any pain, swelling, or other symptoms.

A regular salt water rinse and cold compress application can typically remedy minor irritation, but more serious toothaches may require a dentist’s intervention.

If your symptoms persist for more than a day or two, see your dentist. They can provide guidance on how to relieve your symptoms and prevent future pain.1. Salt water rinse
For many people, a salt water rinse is an effective first-line treatment. Salt water is a natural disinfectant, and it can help loosen food particles and debris that may be stuck in between your teeth.

Treating a toothache with salt waterTrusted Source can also help reduce inflammation and heal any oral wounds.

To use this approach, mix 1/2 teaspoon (tsp) of salt into a glass of warm water and use it as a mouthwash.

2. Hydrogen peroxide rinse
A hydrogen peroxide rinse may also help to relieve pain and inflammation. In addition to killing bacteria, hydrogen peroxide can reduce plaque and heal bleeding gumsTrusted Source.

Make sure you properly dilute the hydrogen peroxide. To do this, mix 3-percent hydrogen peroxide with equal parts water, and use it as a mouthwash. Don’t swallow it.

3. Cold compress
You can use a cold compress to relieve any pain you’re experiencing, especially if any type of trauma has caused your toothache.

When you apply a cold compress, it causes the blood vessels in the area to constrict. This makes pain less severe. The cold can also reduce any swelling and inflammation.

To use this approach, hold a towel-wrapped bag of ice to the affected area for 20 minutes at a time. You can repeat this every few hours.

4. Peppermint tea bags
Peppermint tea bags can be used to numb pain and soothe sensitive gums.

Allow a used tea bag to cool down a little before applying it to the affected area. It should still be slightly warm.

You can also use this method to cool, rather than warm, the area. To do this, put a used tea bag in the freezer for a couple of minutes to chill it and then apply the bag to your tooth. Learn more about the health benefits of peppermint.


5. Garlic
For thousands of years, garlic has been recognized and used for its medicinal properties. It also has antibacterialTrusted Source properties. Not only can it kill harmful bacteriaTrusted Source that cause dental plaque, but it can also act as a pain reliever.

To use garlic on a toothache, crush a garlic clove to create a paste and apply it to the affected area. You may wish to add a tiny bit of salt. Alternatively, you can slowly chew a clove of fresh garlic.

6. Vanilla extract
Vanilla extract contains alcohol, which can help to numb pain. Its proven antioxidantTrusted Source properties also make it an effective healer. Just be sure to use real vanilla rather than imitation vanilla.

To use this remedy, dab a small amount of vanilla extract onto your finger or a cotton ball. Apply it directly to the affected area a few times per day.
7. Clove
Clove has been used to treat toothaches throughout history. The oil can effectively numb pain and reduce inflammationTrusted Source. It contains eugenol, which is a natural antisepticTrusted Source.

To use this approach, dilute clove oil with a carrier oil, like sunflower or jojoba oil. Use a ratio of about 15 drops of clove oil to one ounce of carrier oil, according to the National Association of Holistic Aromatherapy.

Then, dab a small amount of the diluted oil onto a cotton ball and apply it to the affected area a few times a day.

You can also add a drop of clove oil to a small glass of water and make a mouthwash.
    </string>

    <string name="CoolorWarmCompressDES">
        1. Draw a foot bath
A warm foot bath may be just the ticket to alleviating foot pain. Adding Epsom salts to a foot bath can relieve your sore muscles and can even reduce swelling in your feet. You may be tempted to try other products in your foot soak like baking soda, but this ingredient is more likely to target skin-related conditions than soreness or swelling.

You can make an Epsom foot bath by adding one cup of Epsom salts to a tub of warm water. Soak your feet in this mixture for around twenty minutes for relief.


2. Do some stretches
You can also try some stretching exercises to help your sore feet. You can target one area of your foot like your toes or heel, or you can engage in several stretches to target your entire foot. These exercises can prevent cramping and promote flexibility:

Repeat this toe exercise ten times: Flex your toes, point them, and then curl them for a handful of seconds.
Warm up your feet by sitting down and extending your legs. Move your toes around. Point your toes toward your body and away from it. Move your ankles in a circle in both clockwise and counterclockwise directions.
Continue to stretch your feet by shifting your weight from your heels to your toes by taking turns lifting the front and back of your feet off the ground while in a standing position.
3. Practice strengthening exercises
Keeping your feet flexible and strong are keys to avoiding foot pain. Walking regularly for exercise is actually the best way to keep your feet limber and healthy. Avoid engaging in a lifestyle that is too sedentary. A pedometer may be a way to make sure you’re walking enough and keeping your feet active.

You can also try resistance exercises to strengthen your feet and prevent future soreness. You can use resistance bands or weights to build strength in your feet. Even your own body weight can serve you in resistance training.

Here are a few strengthening exercises for your feet:

Try an Achilles stretch with the help of a wall.
Pick up marbles with your toes.
Pull a towel from the floor toward you with your feet while seated to stretch and strengthen your arches.
Attach a resistance band to the foot of a piece of furniture and sit directly across from it in a chair. Pull your foot through the band so it cradles the top of your foot under your toes. Then, pull your foot toward you and hold it in place for a few seconds. Repeat several times. This will stretch your heel.
4. Get a foot massage
You can massage your own feet to help soreness and improve circulation. Sit down in a comfortable chair and rub and knead the bottoms of your feet. Pull apart and bend your toes to massage them. Using lotion or oil can help lubricate your skin, making it easier to massage the foot.

Products like foot rollers (which are textured cylinders), may also help massage the foot if you roll it on the floor with your feet.

5. Buy arch supports
Arch supports, or orthotics, can keep your feet stable while standing or walking, eliminating pain. You can purchase these at the store or have them custom made for you by a doctor. Both have shown to be effective in eliminating rear foot pain and improving overall foot functioning.

See arch supports for purchase online here.

6. Switch your shoes
Your shoes could be the culprit for your foot pain. Wearing shoes beyond their life span, the wrong style of shoe, or an incorrect shoe size can impact the health of your feet.

Keep in mind:

Your sneakers may wear out after 400 or 500 miles and no longer provide the support you need.
High heels and shoes without proper arches or support (like flip-flops) can damage your feet.
Your feet can change in size during your lifetime (even when you’re an adult) because they can spread out over time.
Consider purchasing new, well-fitting shoes to help your aching feet. Shoes that provide proper arches can give your feet new life. Also, wear shoes that work for whatever activity you’re engaging in. For example, wear sneakers when exercising.

7. Ice your feet
Icing your feet can reduce inflammation that causes soreness. Apply ice to sore feet by filling a plastic bag with ice or rolling your feet on a frozen water bottle. Try to ice the affected area for 5 to 15 minutes a few times a day to help reduce inflammation.

8. Take a pain reliever
There are several over-the-counter medications you can try for pain and inflammation. Medications like acetaminophen can target pain, while nonsteroidal anti-inflammatories, like ibuprofen and naproxen sodium, can target pain as well as inflammation.

You may need to take these types of medications for a few weeks to completely relieve long-lasting foot inflammation. It may be helpful to talk to a doctor to find out how long you can take one of these medications and avoid the side effects.

9. Apply a topical pain-relieving medication
You may find that applying a medication topically to your foot helps with foot pain. There are some products available over the counter that offer cooling and pain-relieving sensations. Some of these medications include ingredients like menthol, eucalyptus, and turpentine. Others contain salicylates or substance P to reduce pain.

10. Wear night splints
You may be able to address foot pain while you’re sleeping. Night splints keep your feet in a locked position overnight so you don’t sleep with your feet pointing, which can cause foot pain.

One studyTrusted Source suggests that night splints may be a cost-effective and useful way to treat plantar fasciitis, a common foot condition that affects up to 1 million people per year.

    </string>
    <string name="nauseaDES">
       " A cool or warm compress. Soak a washcloth in either cool or warm water, wring it out, and then put it over the ear that's bothering you. Try both temperatures to see if one helps you more than the other.

A heating pad: Lay your painful ear on a warm, not hot, heating pad.

Over-the-counter ear drops with pain relievers. If they help at all, it’s only briefly. You shouldn’t use these drops if your eardrum has a tear or hole, so check with your doctor first.


Pain reliever. Acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or naproxen can often relieve the pain of an earache. Ask your doctor which is right for you.

Chew gum. If you’re on an airplane or driving at high altitudes and your ear pain is from the change in air pressure, chew some gum. It can help lower that pressure and ease your symptoms.

Sleep upright. While it may sound strange, resting or sleeping sitting up rather than lying down can encourage fluid in your ear to drain. This could ease pressure and pain in your middle ear. Prop yourself up in bed with a stack of pillows, or sleep in an armchair that’s a bit reclined.
   " </string>
</resources>